<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinsmore Design</title>
    <description>We help clients develop their brand, strengthen marketing strategies and acquire life-long customers through creative and visually stunning communication.
</description>
    <link>https://dinsmoredesign.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 15:11:19 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 15:11:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Web Accessibility for Dummies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll be the first to admit it, I was &lt;strong&gt;terrible&lt;/strong&gt; at designing websites to be accessible in the beginning. One might be thinking to themselves, “&lt;em&gt;But Derek, my website looks great to me, why should I care about making it accessible if I don’t have any visually-impaired clients?”&lt;/em&gt; I know, it’s hard to think about others who might have trouble viewing or using your website when you don’t have any disabilities yourself, but you’re really doing your users a disservice by not thinking about everyone who could potentially come across your URL. Just because you don’t currently have any users affected by poor accessibility, doesn’t mean it’s not worth delving into. In fact, many concepts associated with accessibility actually help boost your site’s SEO rankings, because search engine bots can’t see your website, either, they can only read it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hold-on-a-second-what-is-accessibility-again&quot;&gt;Hold on a second. What is accessibility, again?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll go ahead and defer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/accessibility/gettingstarted.html&quot; title=&quot;Adobe's Accessibility Guide&quot;&gt;Adobe&lt;/a&gt;’s own definition here, as I feel like they explain it pretty well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Accessibility involves two key issues: how users with disabilities access electronic information and how web content designers and developers enable web pages to function with assistive devices used by individuals with disabilities. For the user with a disability, the challenge is to identify tools that provide the most convenient access to web-based and other electronic information. For the web content designer/developer, the challenge is to remove the obstacles that prevent accessibility tools from functioning effectively. In many cases, these challenges are relatively simple to overcome, but sometimes the solutions require some additional thought and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wcag-20-and-why-you-should-care-about-accessibility&quot;&gt;WCAG 2.0 and why you should care about accessibility&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W3C’s Web Content Accessibility Guidelines &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/intro/wcag&quot; title=&quot;Visit WCAG website&quot;&gt;(WCAG)&lt;/a&gt; were developed with individuals and organizations around the world to provide standards for web accessibility. As developers, these are the standards and tools we utilize to build accessible websites across the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/standards/webdesign/accessibility&quot; title=&quot;Visit WC3 Accessibility website&quot;&gt;WC3&lt;/a&gt; defines the purpose of the WCAG guidelines as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is essential that the Web be accessible in order to provide equal access and equal opportunity to people with diverse abilities. Indeed, the UN Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities recognizes access to information and communications technologies, including the Web, &lt;strong&gt;as a basic human right.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They go on by saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility supports social inclusion&lt;/strong&gt; for people with disabilities as well as others, such as older people, people in rural areas, and people in developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is also a strong business case for accessibility.&lt;/strong&gt; Accessibility overlaps with other best practices such as mobile web design, device independence, multi-modal interaction, usability, design for older users, and search engine optimization (SEO). Case studies show that accessible websites have better search results, reduced maintenance costs, and increased audience reach, among other benefits. Developing a Web Accessibility Business Case for Your Organization details the social, technical, financial, and legal benefits of web accessibility.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be developing towards their AA standards, at a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-i-test-if-my-site-is-accessible&quot;&gt;How do I test if my site is accessible?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless your site is really simple in its content, it’s pretty unlikely it’ll be &lt;em&gt;fully&lt;/em&gt; accessible from the get-go, but the easiest way to check your site is by refreshing your page and using the keyboard to fully navigate your website utilizing the Tab, Space, Enter and arrow keys. You’ll also want to use a screen reader to make sure your content is read in the correct order by your computer. If you’re using Mac, their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/accessibility/mac/vision/&quot; title=&quot;Visit the Mac VoiceOver website&quot;&gt;VoiceOver&lt;/a&gt; tool is a great start. For Windows, the free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvaccess.org/&quot; title=&quot;Visit the NV Access website&quot;&gt;NVDA&lt;/a&gt; suite is worth checking out, plus the industry-standard, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedomscientific.com/Products/Blindness/JAWS&quot; title=&quot;Visit Job Access With Speech - JAWS - website&quot;&gt;JAWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your keyboard and a screen reader to navigate and read your page can be a real eye-opener for developers who don’t usually build sites for disabled users. Don’t worry, thankfully accessibility has come a long way in the past few years and many standards have emerged that make it even easier to build an accessible website. Keep in mind, this guide is a crash-course on accessibility and the topic can get very dense, the more complex your application is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;accessibility-the-basics&quot;&gt;Accessibility: The Basics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, accessibility really isn’t that hard once you start to develop with it in mind. From a general sense, it really boils down to a few main elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making sure your images and links both contain proper “alt” and “title” attributes with &lt;strong&gt;descriptive&lt;/strong&gt; messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Textual elements provide adequate contrast with their background elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Items that should be clickable are focusable by the keyboard and provide visual cues to the reader when they are selected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Form elements like checkboxes and radio buttons are selectable by keyboard actions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript interactions are controllable by the keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-properly-adding-descriptions-to-images-and-anchors&quot;&gt;1. Properly adding descriptions to images and anchors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever done SEO for a website, you know how important it is to add &lt;em&gt;alt&lt;/em&gt; descriptions to images and &lt;em&gt;titles&lt;/em&gt; to anchor tags, but what you probably didn’t realize is, you’re actually making your website more accessible to visually-impaired readers, too! Think about it: when Google indexes your website, it can’t actually see what’s rendered on a screen, it just reads your markup. That’s exactly how a screenreader works and it’s simple to fix if you haven’t already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The alt Attribute:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “alt” attribute of an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag provides alternative information for an image if a user cannot view it. Not only does this display in place of an image with a broken link, but it’s also read by screen readers and search engines, so they know what the image is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to be as descriptive in your text as possible, ie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;cats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cats playing outside&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to avoid using images containing large amounts of text, but if your image does contain text, enter it in the alt description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;jobpost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wanted: Talented Drupal Developers!&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The title Attribute:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using the title attribute you should be providing information about where you’re sending the user. You should not duplicate the anchor text in a title tag (unless you’re truncating the text within it), as it’s redundant. Use a title tag to support the content within the anchor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio&quot; title=&quot;Check out our portfolio to view more of our work&quot;&amp;gt; See more &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-testing-the-contrast-of-your-pages-content&quot;&gt;2. Testing the contrast of your page’s content&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast is concerned with the size, weight and color of your textual elements over their background content. WCAG 2.0 AA standards require a contrast ratio of 4.5:1 for normal text and 3:1 for large text. Thankfully, you don’t really need to know how to do this, as WebAIM has developed an awesome tool for this! Contrast Checker provides a great resource to verify that your color choice provides a proper contrast ratio, which you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/resources/contrastchecker/&quot; title=&quot;Visit ContrastChecker's webpage&quot;&gt;check out here&lt;/a&gt;. Just enter in your background’s color value and the foreground value and it’ll tell you whether you’re compliant or not! &lt;strong&gt;How’s that for easy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; While not ideal, if your branding requires you to use a certain font color for anchor tags that can’t be changed, a good workaround is giving your link a dark border-bottom that allows your users to easily distinguish the text as a link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-testing-for-properly-focusable-items&quot;&gt;3. Testing for properly focusable items&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test is easy enough, simply navigate your page and start tabbing! You’ll know pretty quickly what is and isn’t focusable, which will give you a good starting point on where to look in your code. It’s also important to make sure your content is highlighted in the correct order. Avoid using too many absolutely-positioned elements, as this can really mess up the order your page is read in. Keep in mind, a screenreader usually reads your content in the order it’s placed in your HTML. If your items are tabbing in the wrong order, you’ll want to check your markup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tabindex Attribute:&lt;/strong&gt; If you run into issues with tabbing that just can’t seem to be fixed in your regular markup, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tabindex=&quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; HTML attribute is here to help. WebAIM cautions that you should only use this attribute, however, if:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The default tab order is not ideal, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The tab order cannot be changed by rearranging items in the content and/or by altering the stylesheet to reflect the best visual arrangement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the tabindex attribute &lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/techniques/keyboard/tabindex&quot; title=&quot;WebAIM on tabindex&quot;&gt;at WebAIM’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note on Focused Elements:&lt;/strong&gt; Many beginning developers disable the built-in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:focus&lt;/code&gt; CSS outline that browsers assign. This is a &lt;strong&gt;big no-no&lt;/strong&gt; when making your site accessible! &lt;strong&gt;Embrace the outline!&lt;/strong&gt; It makes it easier for your readers to see where they’re clicking on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-making-your-form-elements-accessible&quot;&gt;4. Making your form elements accessible&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could easily be a topic in itself, so I won’t go into a lot of detail here. More recently, it’s become common practice for developers to use custom styling on checkboxes and radio buttons, because you cannot directly style the default HTML &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input type=&quot;radio&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, these solutions are rarely ever keyboard accessible and I strongly caution users who don’t already have a strong background in developing accessible websites to stay away from them. The default HTML form elements are accessible by nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to have custom checkboxes or radios, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manuel-strehl.de/dev/on_replacing_checkboxes_with_CSS3.en.html&quot; title=&quot;Accessible custom checkbox tutorial&quot;&gt;tutorial by Manuel Strehl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-accessible-javascript&quot;&gt;5. Accessible JavaScript&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people developing web pages believe that using JavaScript makes the page inaccessible, but that’s just not true. Using JavaScript &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; mean that your page is inaccessible, in fact, with modern screen readers allowing full support of the language, JS is actually a benefit to accessibility in many cases. However, this topic is very vast and requires more advanced knowledge, so I’ll leave this for another time. However, custom JavaScript is often where people run into issues with accessibility on more complex sites. Building a complex menu system that’s fully accessible can be pretty tricky, as well as sliders and other interactive elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WebAIM’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/techniques/javascript/&quot; title=&quot;Learn about accessible JavaScript from WebAIM&quot;&gt;article on accessible JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is a great start for those of you wanting to learn more, but for beginners, I’d suggest starting with an accessible CSS/JS framework and make it easier on yourself. While most other frameworks definitely keep accessibility in mind, &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/sites/docs/accessibility.html&quot; title=&quot;Foundation 6's accessibility documentation&quot;&gt;Foundation 6 for Sites&lt;/a&gt; is currently the only fully-accessible CSS and JavaScript framework on the market… and it’s totally free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advanced-readings&quot;&gt;Advanced Readings:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Accessibility/ARIA&quot; title=&quot;Learn about ARIA from the Mozilla Developer Network&quot;&gt;Accessible Rich Internet Applications (ARIA)&lt;/a&gt; - a set of special accessibility attributes which can be added to any markup, but is especially suited to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/intro/&quot; title=&quot;Read the Intro to Web Accessibility&quot;&gt;WebAIM’s Intro to Web Accessibility&lt;/a&gt; - A quick overview to web accessibility and its development throughout the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com/course/web-accessibility--ud891&quot; title=&quot;Take the free web accessibility course by Google on Udacity&quot;&gt;Udacity Web Accessibility&lt;/a&gt; - A free course developed by Google for the Udacity platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a question or a favorite resource for accessibility? Let us know in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/accessibility-for-dummies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/accessibility-for-dummies/</guid>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>tips &amp; tricks</category>
        
        <category>SEO</category>
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
        
        <category>development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to do when you think your Gmail was hacked.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we move into an increasingly technology-dependent era, unfortunately, “hacked” email accounts have become increasingly more common. If you think you’ve been affected, don’t worry, you’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common way of hacking your email account is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phishing&quot; title=&quot;Read the Wikipedia article on Phishing&quot;&gt;phishing&lt;/a&gt;, or “the fraudulent practice of sending emails purporting to be from reputable companies in order to induce individuals to reveal personal information, such as passwords and credit card numbers.” While phishing is always a threat, in light of a recent nation-wide attack on Gmail, we’ve put together a quick guide on how to identify and protect yourself against phishing scams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of a phishing email is shown below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing_top.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of phishing scam&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of phishing scam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-spot-a-phishing-email&quot;&gt;How to spot a phishing email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(And how to protect yourself from future attacks)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackers are becoming more sophisticated in their efforts; it can be difficult to distinguish a legitimate email from a fake one, especially if it’s coming from a person you know. While phishing scams usually start with a random sender, as soon as your account is compromised by clicking the link contained within it, the hacker will log into your account and distribute the email, &lt;strong&gt;as you&lt;/strong&gt;, to everyone on your contacts list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, the email can look legitimate, by disguising itself as someone sharing a Google Doc with you, or sending a survey for you to take. In other cases, they may use a linked URL that looks to go to a legitimate web address, but actually, goes to a different location than specified (like in the image below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Google Docs phishing scam&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of Google Docs phishing scam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above, is a screenshot of an actual phishing scam that recently affected Gmail users. While it appears to be potentially legitimate because of the styling of the button, take a look at an actual email Google would send you with a shared Google Doc below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Real shared Google Docs email&quot; title=&quot;Real shared Google Docs email&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’ll see, the original email had a lot missing. However, that’s not to say that you’ll never see a phishing scam that looks exactly like what a company like Google would send you; it &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; happen. After all, they did identically copy the “Open in Docs” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While simply looking at the email and seeing that something looks phishy (ha, see what I did there!?) is usually a great first indicator, the best way to tell if an email is legitimate or not is by inspecting the actual links within the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s important to note that, simply opening an email containing a phishing scam &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; mean your account was immediately infected. You have to physically click a button or link and (usually) enter some kind of information or give permission to something in order for your account to be compromised.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-inspect-the-links-of-an-email-for-legitimate-urls&quot;&gt;How to inspect the links of an email for legitimate URLs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is actually more simple than you’d think!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re on a desktop or laptop computer…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hover your mouse over the button or link and look in the bottom left-hand corner of your browser’s page. The URL of the link will display here. In the real example above, hovering over the button shows the following URL on the bottom left of the screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example URL when hovering over link&quot; title=&quot;Example URL when hovering over link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your browser doesn’t support this feature, you can alternatively right-click the link and select “Copy Link Address” (this title may be different depending on your browser) and then paste it into a text editor to check where you’re navigating to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Right clicking a link to select copy link address&quot; title=&quot;Right clicking a link to select copy link address&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re on a mobile device…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place your finger over the link and long-hold until a popup opens. On Android, this will display the link’s truncated URL and give you the ability to copy it, so you can paste it somewhere else to view the entire address. The function is very similar on iOS devices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of URL on Android&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of URL on Android&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these instances, you’re inspecting the address to see if it looks legitimate. &lt;strong&gt;The URL should go to a web address you recognize.&lt;/strong&gt; In this case, the URL &lt;strong&gt;starts with&lt;/strong&gt; google.com, a website we recognize and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re in doubt, don’t click it!&lt;/strong&gt; Contact the person who sent you the message and ask if it’s legitimate, or delete the email if it’s not important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ive-already-clicked-the-link-my-account-is-hacked&quot;&gt;I’ve already clicked the link, my account is hacked!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Don’t worry, it’ll be okay! Take a deep breath and follow the directions below.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-reset-your-password&quot;&gt;Step 1: Reset your password&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your account has been compromised, the first step you need to take is to change your Google password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sign into your My Account page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the “Sign-in &amp;amp; security” section, select &lt;strong&gt;Signing in to Google &amp;gt; Password&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type your current password and your new password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Change password&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/settings/passwordchange&quot; title=&quot;Change your Google password&quot;&gt;direct link&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re already signed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-revoke-account-permission-to-unknown-apps&quot;&gt;Step 2: Revoke account permission to unknown apps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to https://myaccount.google.com/permissions and inspect the permissions associated with your Google account. If you notice any apps you don’t remember giving permissions to, click “Revoke”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing11.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google App Permissions&quot; title=&quot;Google App Permissions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-sign-out-other-web-sessions&quot;&gt;Step 3: Sign out other web sessions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside your email’s inbox, scroll to the bottom of the page, you should see in the bottom right-hand corner a link that says “Open in &lt;em&gt;__ other location: Details” (the __&lt;/em&gt; would be the number of locations your email is currently signed in from). Click the &lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt; link:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing12.png&quot; alt=&quot;Details link at bottom right hand corner of Inbox&quot; title=&quot;Details link at bottom right hand corner of Inbox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new window will open. If anything is listed under “Concurrent Session Information”, click the button below it that says “&lt;strong&gt;Sign out all other web sessions&lt;/strong&gt;”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing10.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign out all other web sessions&quot; title=&quot;Sign out all other web sessions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-4-remove-unwanted-device-access&quot;&gt;Step 4: Remove unwanted device access&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to https://myaccount.google.com/device-activity and inspect the listed devices on your account. If a device is listed that you don’t recognize, click on it in the list and select “&lt;strong&gt;Remove&lt;/strong&gt;”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Device Activity&quot; title=&quot;Google Device Activity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-5-remove-unwanted-email-filters&quot;&gt;Step 5: Remove unwanted email filters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When logged into your email, click the gear icon at the top right, then go to Settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Settings dropdown in Gmail&quot; title=&quot;Settings dropdown in Gmail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, navigate to the Filters and Blocked Addresses tabs. If there’s anything listed that you didn’t enter in yourself, delete it (if you’ve never created an email filter, this list should be blank):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phishing/phishing7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gmail Filters&quot; title=&quot;Gmail Filters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions?&lt;/strong&gt; Let us know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/identifying-and-protecting-yourself-against-phishing-gmail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/identifying-and-protecting-yourself-against-phishing-gmail/</guid>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
        <category>tips &amp; tricks</category>
        
        <category>phishing</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Resources for Beginning Web Developers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning web development can be hard. There are so many different technologies out there that it’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard to figure out what you should be learning. Whether you’re just learning for fun, or want to make a career out of it, these resources will help you get a jump-start on your learning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-codecademy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;Visit Codecademy's Website&quot;&gt;1. Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/codecademy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Codecademy&quot; title=&quot;Codecademy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codecademy is an interactive website that lets you learn all kinds of programming languages. The site’s guided tutorials are great for teaching the basics skills to help you be productive quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the site’s recent redesign and all the new courses, Codecademy is a force to be reckoned with in the online-learning spectrum. However, while Codecademy is mostly free, they recently released a paid, “Pro,” version which allows you to get guidance from advisors and a specialized learning plan with projects that aren’t available to unpaid customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I wouldn’t be bothered by the upgraded version of their service, since they still allow you to use the basic features for free, but most of their new course offerings only give you a small subset of knowledge on the subjects. They require that you pay to learn the portions you most likely wanted to learn in the first place. Courses like their AngularJS 1.X class only gives you about 25% of the total course, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t had a chance to try out their paid service yet, but their courses in JavaScript, HTML &amp;amp; CSS, Git and others are invaluable to beginning developers, as they allow you to instantly become confident in your skills, by showing you your results right there on the screen. I’d definitely recommend Codecademy to anyone starting out a complete beginner level, or even if you’re an experienced dev and just want to get your feet wet in a new technology without reading extensive documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-css-tricks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/&quot; title=&quot;Visit CSS-Tricks's Website&quot;&gt;2. CSS-Tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/css-tricks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CSS-Tricks&quot; title=&quot;CSS-Tricks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS-Tricks is a great resource as a repository for front-end development tips and much more around the web. Subscribing to their blog gives you daily ideas to implement in your website designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don’t specifically use CSS-Tricks as a learning resource, there are very few instances where I’m trying to figure out a UI component to implement, where I can’t load up their website and find exactly what I needed. The site is amazing for use as a reference to more experienced devs who are looking for more specific knowledge on certain things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, they do have a really extensive listing of videos on the site that go through some really interesting topics, like building games with JavaScript, SVG animations and Photoshop design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-freecodecamp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Visit FreeCodeCamp's Website&quot;&gt;3. FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/fcc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FreeCodeCamp&quot; title=&quot;FreeCodeCamp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the discipline to stick to it, FreeCodeCamp’s curriculum will get you from zero to professional utilizing the latest JavaScript technologies. You’ll learn front-end and full-stack development with Node.JS and React.JS, plus essential algorithm skills. Not only that but by the time you’ve completed the curriculum, you’ll have a plethora of projects to show off to employers to get you the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FCC’s business model is very novel, in fact. Their ultimate purpose is to give you the skills you need to be successful and then get you in contact with non-profit organizations to develop your portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curriculum is definitely not for the faint of heart, but it’s by far, the most extensive online experience I’ve seen and best of all, it’s &lt;strong&gt;completely free&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a favorite I haven’t listed? Let us know in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/3-resources-for-beginning-web-developers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/3-resources-for-beginning-web-developers/</guid>
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
        <category>tips &amp; tricks</category>
        
        
        <category>development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Beginning Designers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For several years, I’ve maintained this website as a digital timeline of my favorite work. I’ve used it to showcase my work to potential clients, but most importantly, I’ve used it to document the purpose of each project and my development as a designer. As someone who’s worked for an educational institution for most of my professional career, teaching things has always been a passion and it’s my hope that with this post, and the ones to follow, I can help up-and-coming designers be the best they can be. So, let’s get into it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to touch on the subject of education, and by that, I mean, &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; education as a designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy math or, at least, paid a little attention during geometry, let me lay it out for you in a way you might be able to understand. Remember how all squares are rectangles, but not all rectangles are squares? Graphic design is the opposite:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some art is graphic design, but not all graphic design is art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean to say is, there are some designers who make art and there are others who create functional materials. There’s certainly room for both (and art can certainly crossover to the functional), but if you’re considering a career in design, I’m here to tell you that you don’t necessarily need to have any eye for art, there are far more important skills to hone. While pieces of design that could be considered art may look exciting, they’re very often impractical and finding a use for it in everyday business is slim to none. This is the kind of design your mom is scared of you to get into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/adobe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Adobe Creative Cloud Icons&quot; title=&quot;Adobe Creative Cloud Icons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-learn-the-appropriate-tools-of-the-trade-work-smart-and-youll-get-things-done-quicker&quot;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Learn the appropriate tools of the trade.&lt;/strong&gt; Work smart and you’ll get things done quicker.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adobe pretty much has the lock on the design world. While there are certainly other programs out there worth learning, it will be expected of you to be able to work in the Adobe ecosystem at any job you’re likely to find. As a designer who started out heavily focused on print, it’s a pet peeve of mine when I see people using the wrong programs for certain things. As a manager at a creative firm, I would be very weary of your skills and knowledge if I saw you utilizing these programs inappropriately. Each Adobe product is tailored toward a certain thing it’s meant to do well and its workflow is built around these things. By utilizing something different, you’re wasting time and potentially making decisions that can’t be changed later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photoshop&lt;/strong&gt;‘s strengths lie in photo editing and digital art. While you can do layout design in it, it’s not built to deal with vectors, typography, and multiple resolutions like others are. Use this program to make adjustments to your photos, backgrounds, etc. that you’d import into a layout design program. The only instance where I’d consider using Photoshop as a layout tool would be for web graphics, but even then, I feel like there are better ways to go about it. I would not suggest building logos in Photoshop as you’re mostly dealing with raster images that won’t upscale well – sure, you can make the initial file huge, but that just takes up more space on your hard drive than is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illustrator&lt;/strong&gt; is for vector graphics. This is where you want to build logos and any graphic you want to be able to scale nicely across many resolutions and sizes. Illustrator isn’t as easy to work with when it comes to photorealism as Photoshop is, but that’s not really the purpose of the program, either. Graphics should be simple and easy to understand and Illustrator has the most precise tools to help you create a fluid and crisp line plus exact breakpoints. While I’ve used it to do some really intricate work, it’s not something I’d really suggest you, master, as you could likely do it quicker somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InDesign&lt;/strong&gt; is for layout. If you’re planning on being a graphic designer and don’t know InDesign, forget what you’re doing in Photoshop and drop what you’re doing in Illustrator. You &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to learn InDesign. Just the other day, I ran into a website that had some really cool, creative, resume templates but as I investigated more, I realized that every single one of them was made in Photoshop. Why?? You’re doing way too much work! The layouts they’d created in Photoshop, undoubtedly, took them hours to create because Photoshop’s workflow isn’t tailored for layout, it’s tailored for photo editing. The same exact work would’ve taken a matter of minutes to create in InDesign and if the size of the page needed to be changed, it could be done within a matter of seconds, without pixelating any of the elements. As a designer (especially one who specializes in print), you will live in InDesign. Learn it well. Learn it deeply. Embrace it and learn to love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/digitaliso.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DigitalISO Logos&quot; title=&quot;DigitalISO Logos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-learn-the-difference-between-designing-for-print-and-designing-for-the-web&quot;&gt;2. Learn the difference between designing for print and designing for the web.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two totally different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in the industry throw around the terms PPI and DPI so much that you’re going to think they have no idea what they’re talking about. DPI refers to the dots per inch of a printer, PPI refers to the pixels per inch of an image. Most of the time, when someone tells you they need a 300 DPI image, they really mean PPI. It’s confusing, I know. &lt;strong&gt;Pro-tip&lt;/strong&gt;: If you don’t know what the printer is talking about, ask! They’ll be glad you did and it’ll save you extra work in the future. In fact, I always ask a new printer for their print specifications before I even start building something, it just makes things easier. Heck, you might even learn a thing or two that you’ll be glad you knew later down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn about bleeds and why it might be okay to use them for the web, but might end up costing you more in print. Sure, it might look great for your colors to run all the way to the edge of a piece of paper, but it’s also more expensive (you’ll have to pay for 11×17″ pages, only to receive an 8.5×11″ once it’s cut down). Know your customer and know their budget, if you can save them some money by doing something differently, they’re going to love you for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn about the printing process itself. While certain colors may display great on the web, you might have to adjust them for print because of the way it works and vice versa. Smaller type might also be easier to read on a printed piece of paper while being impossible to read on the web. If you’ll be designing shirts or other apparel, check to see if it’s being screen printed, if it is – there’s a lot of things you can’t do because of the limitations of the process and the number of colors you can use. Your exciting design might end up being flat and boring; knowing your limitations from the start will help you design something great from the get-go, rather than altering it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/nike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nike Ad&quot; title=&quot;Nike Ad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-pay-attention-to-advertisements&quot;&gt;3. Pay attention to advertisements.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say imitation is the greatest form of flattery and you’re going to be doing a lot of imitation at first. That’s okay! &lt;em&gt;Well… as long as you’re not blatantly ripping off someone’s work, I mean!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in school, I really only focused on doing my own thing. I learned color theory and the printing process but was mostly oblivious to design in the real world, despite studying trends. It wasn’t until I graduated and started working in the industry that I really started noticing good design. In school, we’re all attracted to the colorful works that lean more toward art. If you were paying attention above, these certainly have their place, but they’re not practical in business. If you study a successful business’s ads you’ll soon realize why their campaigns are successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design in business is about building a brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quicker you realize and embrace this, the more successful you’ll be. Design and branding go hand-in-hand, it all ties into marketing. Agencies carefully select colors and images to convey their message. Strong promotional materials are successful because they follow guidelines that strengthen the overall brand or cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/material.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Material Design Background&quot; title=&quot;Material Design Background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-pay-attention-to-colors-and-fonts&quot;&gt;4. Pay attention to colors and fonts.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going along with the above section, colors can invoke certain psychological emotions and some of the biggest brands in the world are built around these concepts. They can also tell the story of a company, without even using any words. Learn about color psychology and what colors are appropriate for certain sectors of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like colors, fonts can also invoke emotion. A handwritten font may look more inviting but when overused, can seem childish. Scripts can make great headers or callout sections, but are hard to read in excess. Sans-serif are currently the “in” font but there’s a reason Serif is still a classic. Both have their uses and can also be great when utilized together. &lt;strong&gt;Pro-tip&lt;/strong&gt;: If the purpose of the piece is to remain as readable as possible, try to limit your materials to 2-3 fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/audience.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Audience at a Concert&quot; title=&quot;Concert Audience&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-figure-out-who-your-audience-is&quot;&gt;5. Figure out who your audience is.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my years as a designer, I’ve seen some great design and I’ve also seen a lot of terrible design. In education, especially, this happens far too often. Teachers and administrators make a flyer, website or pamphlet that they want the parent to read, yet they design it appeal to the child instead. Sure, they might think it’s cute but they’re forgetting the number one rule of design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know who your audience is and tailor your piece to them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m sure these parents are still going to read the information because they care about their child’s education, they’re not going to be engaged and they probably won’t retain much of the information in the end. Remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Design is not always about making things look pretty. Effective design is characterized by the attributes that maximize functionality and make things easy to understand. &lt;strong&gt;Good design that will stand the test of time is, at its core, simple.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Code on Screen&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot of Code on Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;an-aside-learn-to-code&quot;&gt;An Aside: Learn to code.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many jobs I’ve seen posted recently that are listed as “graphic design” jobs, yet the qualifications listed are almost all “web design” related. Yes, ladies and gents, you’re going to need to learn to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my degree program at ASU, I took several web design courses and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;hated&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; every single one of them. It wasn’t the instructor’s faults, the content isn’t exactly the most exciting to convey, especially when we didn’t think we’d need to know these things once we went into the industry. Boy were we wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are still graphic-only related jobs out there, they mostly only exist in the print industry or require experience far and above that of which you’ll come out of college with. Thankfully, my school also gave me a great background in business and marketing which has helped me greatly, but I was still under the impression that I could graduate and move into a management degree, or at the very least, something that wasn’t a junior position. Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t expect to get paid much as a graphic designer&lt;/strong&gt;, at least in the beginning. While it’s a very important part of marketing, few companies seem to really understand the value of a good designer; don’t be surprised if you’re making less than $15 an hour at first. There are high paying jobs out there, but they are very competitive because these companies know they’re going to have the pick of the litter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graphic design&lt;/em&gt; has become a very broad term over the years. Today’s graduates should be expected to learn HTML, CSS and, at least, a little JavaScript. &lt;em&gt;Graphic design&lt;/em&gt; jobs with web duties may not expect you to build entire web pages from the ground up, but if you, at least, have a good understanding of how to take your design from your mockup to a live landing page, you’re going to get a lot more interviews. Soon, &lt;em&gt;the front-end developer will be the new graphic designer&lt;/em&gt; and the quicker you embrace this, the better. Hey, it also helps that you’ll make a lot more money off the bat, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not excited about your program’s approach to learning to code? &lt;a href=&quot;http://codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start. It’s interactive and they actually teach you skills that are useful in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there we have it, it was long (sorry about that!), but I hope this article can, at least, help someone out there. If you have any questions, please, feel free to ask. I’d love to help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for some more resources to learn a little more?  Check these out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1stwebdesigner.com/print-and-web-design/&quot;&gt;Graphic Design Basics for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://designschool.canva.com/blog/print-vs-web/&quot;&gt;Graphic Design for Print vs The Web: 15 Vital Differences You Need To Know About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onextrapixel.com/2012/03/01/the-difference-between-print-and-web-design/&quot;&gt;The Difference Between Print and Web Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/5-tips-for-beginning-designers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dinsmoredesign.comhttps://dinsmoredesign.com/blog/5-tips-for-beginning-designers/</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>graphic design</category>
        
        <category>web design</category>
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
        <category>tips &amp; tricks</category>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
